<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cinephilia on ninjaduck</title>
    <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/categories/cinephilia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cinephilia on ninjaduck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 13:35:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ninjaducks.in/categories/cinephilia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>La La Land - The Ending</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/la-la-land</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/la-la-land</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La La Land is a remarkable movie in many ways. Even its name is a pun upon the city of L.A., the home of Hollywood, where the movie is set. It is a musical love story of Mia - a struggling actress and Sebastian - a jazz pianist, talented but unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BMzUzNDM2NzM2MV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwNTM3NTg4OTE@._V1_QL50_SY500_SX675_AL_.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

I feel that its the ending of the movie that gives it its true character. When both of them have achieved their creative ambitions- Mia is a successful actress and is married with a kid, Sebastian owns a jazz bar of his own, they meet again when Mia happens to go to Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s jazz club with her husband. Sebastian is on the stage and sees her. This meeting, given they meet after 5 years, feels surreal. It can&amp;rsquo;t be that both of them had not anticipated this moment. Sebastian approaches the piano and plays the music he was playing the second time they had met. This music had been a recurring motif in their lives and had driven many of their decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mia and Sebastian imagine their entire life till that point together, both - the parts they spent together and the parts they did not, in one beautiful song and it seems all so perfect. All the unpleasant moments from their lives are altered to show a flawless fairy tale reimagination. They imagine all the unrealized possibilies of their relationship. When the music ends, Mia wakes up from a trance and decides to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Mia is leaving, their eyes meet. For a moment, nothing happens, they just look at each other. This moment is full of anticipation and tension. In this moment, or rather the entirety of this unexpected meeting, both of them are not sure what they want from each other, whether they would be happy if they get back together again or not. Both of them have been hit by a strong wave of nostalgia, which being the strangest of all emotions tries to makes people sad and happy at the same time. Then Mia, smiles. She is probably realizing that the time they spent together would always remain with her as beautiful memories of the past and she wanted it to be that way. There was too much inertia to getting back together again, and it was not the best thing to do at that time. A moment later, Sebastian smiles too. To me, this scene is evocative of the deep connection they both share, having been with each other, supporting each other at perhaps the most difficult times in their lives. Then Mia leaves and the movie ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it a feel good movie and the ending a happy one? It is hard to characterize. But it sure is different from all the other movies I have seen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review – Akira(1988)</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/akira-review</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/akira-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ninjaducks.in/images/akira-poster.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Akira is a quintessential cyberpunk movie. What is cyberpunk? It is this cool subgenre of Science Fiction which is characterized by a post-apocalyptic dystopian society and advanced technology. Common cyberpunk themes often deal with the role of advanced technology like artificial intelligence in human lives, the moral and philosophical issues they raise. It often raises the question – “What does it mean to be human?”. Many films adopt a film-noir style and have a dark, skeptical tone. Its protagonists are generally fringe elements of the society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening scene of the movie shows a huge explosion, which engulfs and destroys all of Tokyo. The sound of the explosion is not heard, just the ghostly, howling winds in its aftermath which is kind of unsettling and sets the dark tone for the entire movie. This event happens in 1988 which marks the starting of the World War III. The actual movie takes place in a new and rebuilt Neo Tokyo, 31 years after the Third World War, in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ninjaducks.in/images/akira-buildings.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Neo Tokyo is a technologically advanced and massively urbanized city with awe inspiring huge skyscrapers stacked one on top of each other, glowing neon lights and advertisements everywhere.  Most of the scenes in the movie show highly advanced technology even in the meanest things. Then, there are also parts of the city which are in ruins. There are damaged, dilapidated buildings, which are in dire state of repair everywhere. The streets are full of junk and discarded items, walls are riddled with graffiti and posters.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ninjaducks.in/images/surveillance.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The society of Neo Tokyo is unstable and decadant. There is a lot of political unrest in the city. Citizens rebel and riot frequently against the imperialist political regime, causing lots of destruction of life and property. The rebellions are brutally and mercilessly crushed by the police. People can be seen in mass gatherings shouting, raising slogan, waving flags, burning up cars and fighting the police. Another noticeable facet of the society is the ubiquity of surveillance. There seem to be lights everywhere searching for people. Perhaps the eye like lights from helicopters searching for a kid in the dark, following his actions is a metaphor for mass surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main characters of the movie are teenagers who race around the city on their bikes in a gang and frequently clash with other such gangs. They hang out in a shady bar which is frequented by other transgressors of the law induging in illicit activities. A scene shows their school as the opposite of the bustling instituion of fun and learning that they generally are. Everything in the school from walls, corridors and furniture to the students is dirty. The students are undisciplined and not treated properly.
On the contrary, the high society of the city an also be seen roaming around in huge malls and restraunts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more happening in the movie to be able to grasp in a single watch. Directed by Katsuhiro Otomo, it is a 2-hour movie made out of a 6 volume manga. The story follows three main group of characters - Kaneda and Tetsuo, Colonel Shikishima and Doctor Onishi, and the rebels - Ryu and Kei. Kaneda and Tetsuo are childhood friends and member of the same motorcycle gang, whose leader is Kaneda. During an accident, Tetsuo comes in contact with Takashi, a psychic child in care of the government, and himself gains psychokinetic powers. Tetsuo is captured by the army and hospitalized where he is closely monitored by Doctor Onishi. He starts suffering from psychic migranes and has visions of mysterious being called Akira. It all starts going wrong from there. Bossed around his entire life, for the first time Tetsuo feels powerful, starts resenting Kaneda, becomes arrogant and starts misusing his powers.  He comes to know about the whereabouts of Akira from one of the other psychic children under government care and starts on a mission to confront him, destroying the city in the process. Meanwhile, the rebels plot down the fall of the corrupt government, the government, Colonel Shikishima tries to prevent the destruction of the city on the hands of Tetsuo and Doctor Onishi is studies development of power in Tetsuo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie is action packed and entertaining with many high speed bike chases throughout. Lots of destruction is shown as Tetsuo destroys bridges, stadiums and other building throughout the city. For the entirety of the movie, the mysterious being Akira is left unexplained. He is so mysterious that there is a growing religious cult that proclaim him as their God. This ironic incident has the potential of exposing the relationship between technology and religion in a hi-tech, yet crumbling society. Also left unexplained are the psychic powers of the three children under government care. Time delved on the rebels is too less to build any comprehensible story out of it. Character development is also lacking in many of the major character like Kei as they get very less screen time. Since the manga was too long for a 2 hour movie, most of the subplots have been cut so short, it is hard to understand them. Even though the emotional depth of the characcter is overshadowed by the depth of the dystopian world built by the director Katsuhiro Otomo, it would be hard to criticize the movie on its shallow characters as it leaves the audience spellbound with its sheer intensity in every frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One notable feature of the movie is its distinct soundtrack which is very different from other typical anime movies of the time. The ominous drum beats that build up anticipation, the bell chimes mixed with chants during the high speed bike chases, the explosive electronic music during the high-adrenaline fight sequences are very apt for the scenes. The animation of the movie is nothing short of exceptional. It is extremely detailed and rich. Some novel techniques were used in the animating the movie. According to Wikipedia -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most anime was notorious for cutting production corners with limited animation, such as having only the characters&amp;rsquo; mouths move with basic lip sync while their faces remained static. Akira broke from this trend with detailed scenes, pre-scored dialogue (wherein the dialogue is recorded before the film starts production and the movements of the characters&amp;rsquo; lips are animated to match it; a first for an anime production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The director does not hold back in showing bloody violence and lots of gore in the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Akira is widely acclaimed to be one of the best animated movies ever made. This was the movie that made anime popular in western countries and has gained a cult status. I was utterly mesmerized by the world built by the director Katsuhiro Otomo. Watching this movie was a unique experience. I will give it a rating of &lt;strong&gt;9 / 10&lt;/strong&gt; and recommned everyone to watch it atleast once.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review – J.S.A.: Joint Security Area</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/jsa-review</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/jsa-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/7f/Jsa.movist.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

J.S.A.: Joint Security Area is a South Korean movie directed by the amazing Park Chan Wook. JSA was his first successful movie both critically and commercially. Based on the novel &amp;ldquo;DMZ&amp;rdquo; by Park Sang-yeon, J.S.A tells the story of an incident that happened on the DMZ (Demilitarized Zone) between North and South Korea which involved death of two North Korean soldiers, presumably by a South Korean soldier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit of history to explain the hostility between North and South Korea – At the end of World War two, after the surrender of Japanese forces, Korea was divided into two states, with the North under Soviet occupation and the South under U.S. occupation. The communist government in North Korea received backing from Soviet Union and the democracy in South was backed by USA which eventually led to Korean War in 1950. Korean War ended in a stalemate in 1953 without any side winning. As part of the Cease-fire Agreement, a 4km-wide Demilitarized Zone (DMZ) was created to act as a buffer between the North and South. A Joint Security Area was also created in Panmunjom, where discussions between the two sides can take place. The major incidents of the movie take place at this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the face of it, the movie is a mainstream thriller. A crime happens, some people die and an investigation is called. The movie starts with a Swiss military officer of Korean ancestry - Major Sophie Jean arriving in Panmunjom to conduct the investigation called on by both the Koreas. Due to the mutual distrust between the two nations, the investigation is to be conducted by a neutral third party - Neutral Nations Supervisory Commission (NNSC). The depositions have already been filed by the soldiers involved from both sides and she soon starts finding inconsistencies in them. Despite the political themes being at the center of the film, it quickly moves away from them to tell a different story. Major Sophie Jean&amp;rsquo;s story is soon sidelined by a separate narrative, the story of a doomed friendship between two North Korean and two South Korean soldiers. The director does not try to build suspense and the timeline of the movie continuously shifts between past and present showing the actual version of the events that happened and the investigation being carried on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual version of events that happened show a tragic end to a doomed friendship between two South Korean and two North Korean soldiers. A random scene, which shows Sgt. Oh handing over the cap of an American tourist which has flown over to the North side on the North-South border tries to establish his character. A high angle shot is used which very clearly and geometrically shows the border separating the two nations. Another tourist tries to take a photograph of Sgt. Oh, even though photography is prohibited. One night during an expedition a group of South Korean soldiers stray into North Korea&amp;rsquo;s land and hastily leave when they realize their mistake. The protagonist of the movie, Sgt. Lee gets left behind. To make it worse, he realizes that he is trapped in a land-mine. He struggles unsuccessfully to dismantle it. Right then, two North Korean soldiers, including Sgt. Oh, come by. In a comical scene where both the parties are unsure what to do as it is an unprecedented situation for them, there is a struggle which ends in a stalemate as Sgt. Lee is standing on a mine and can trip it to kill all of them. As the other two start to leave him in his miserable condition, he starts crying. Taking pity on him, Sgt. Oh helps him dismantle the mine and sets him free. The initial mistrust and animosity between these enemy soldiers is dissolved by this act of kindness to pave way for a possible friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sgt. Lee keeps on seeing the two North Korean soldiers at different times during his duties. Then one night when Sgt. Lee and his friend, Pvt. Nam are on guard duty, Sgt. Lee decides to send a letter to the two soldiers on the other side. He gets a favorable response from the other side and starts communicating with them on a regular basis. Another fateful night, when his companion is asleep, he takes the initiative and crosses the border to visit the guard post on the other side! After the two North Korean soldiers recover from the initial shock, they welcome him and after this initial meeting, the three of them start meeting regularly. Then one night, Sgt. Lee brings along Pvt. Nam along with him to meet his new friends. The next few months show a flourishing friendship between the four of them. We see them drinking together, playing games like little kids, sharing little things about their life with one another. Until it all ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment for which we all had been waiting for arrives when a North Korean officer visits the guard post while all four of them are there. The melancholy music playing in the background suddenly stops when not knowing what to make of the situation, he pulls out his gun an points it on the two South Korean soldiers. Sgt. Lee tries to mediate and bring the situation under control. The bonds of friendship are tested when no one knows how to react to the situation and life of everyone is under threat. That deep initial mistrust between the people of the two nationalities resurfaces. In a moment of clarity, Sgt. Lee realizes the mistake he had made in considering that such a friendship was possible. The melancholy music resumes as the action unfolds. I will not spoil the complete movie by telling all the details. Lots of things happen after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ninjaducks.in/images/jsa.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

In the end, only Sgt. Oh survives. The last shot of the movie pans over the photograph which the tourist took. This photograph is probably the only photograph where all four of them are together, even though it was not taken with that intention. Sgt. Oh is standing directly in the front of the camera with a mystic, probably satisfied smile on his face. The other North Korean soldier, Pvt. Jeong  can be seen marching behind the border and was fortunate enough to look into the camera at the right time and is amused by the incident taking place. Pvt. Nam is standing guard along with hero, and did not forget to look into the camera. Sgt. Lee is trying to stop the tourist from taking the picture and can be seen waving his hand in front of the camera. This candid shot of the four characters has a lasting affect and is evocative of a pleasant nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ninjaducks.in/images/jsa1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ninjaducks.in/images/jsa2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Throughout the movie, the borders between the two countries have been very pronounced and clearly shown in many scenes, but is very cleverly hidden in this photograph. The four of them can be seen for what they are, ignoring any difference in their nationalities. Looking at just this photograph, you can&amp;rsquo;t see any reason why the friendship between the four of them can be forbidden. It demands an answer to the question - why can&amp;rsquo;t they be friends, as the humans they are. Should the struggle between two political ideologies result in such a tragic end of an innocent comradeship?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I will give it &lt;strong&gt;8 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;. The visual style that Park Chan Wook is famous for can be seen in its nascent form in this movie. It may not be Park Chan Wook&amp;rsquo;s best works, but is still a good watch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anime Binge Watch - Erased</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/erased-review</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/erased-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After finishing my M.Tech thesis, I had some free time on my hands. It was an ideal situation to satiate my gluttonous appetite for some movies/tv. This time I chose to watch some long outstanding anime. Despite animes having some excellent stroylines and amazing characters, I had been withholding the urge to watch them for a long time due their addictive/bingeworthy nature.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/10/77957.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first anime I binge-watched was &lt;a href=&#34;http://myanimelist.net/anime/31043/Boku_dake_ga_Inai_Machi&#34;&gt;Boku dake ga Inai Machi&lt;/a&gt; (The Town Where Only I am Missing) also known as &lt;code&gt;Erased&lt;/code&gt; in English. Releases in January 2016, it has just 12 episodes of 20 minutes each and can be easily watched in a single sitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erased is a fantasy thriller. Though there is not much fantasy in it. The protagonist of the story is Satoru Fujinuma, a 29 year old manga writer who has a supernatural abiility known as &lt;code&gt;Revival&lt;/code&gt; that allows him to be sent back in time to prevent deaths and casualties around him. Generally, a revial sends Staoru back a few minutes in time. When his mother visits him and gets mysteriously killed, he is sent back 18 years in time to prevent her death. Satoru now decides to save one of his classmates - Kayo Hinazuki, who he remembers having died in a series of child abduction cases that struck his locality 18 years ago. It is shown that Satoru blames himself for not being able to save Kayo. One of his childhood friends was also falsely set-up and convicted for these murders. He also wants to change the future by saving Kayo to prevent his mother from getting killed. This sets up the rest of the anime where he tries to save first Kayo, and then the other victims from the murderer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fair amount of time is delved in trying to change the things from as they has happened the last time, trying to anticipate the actions and methods of the enemy and trying to alter things reasonably to save Kayo. Kayo is a recluse and a victim of child abuse by her mother. Satoru tries to befriend her and keep her from the harm&amp;rsquo;s way. The plot is very interesting. There are enough thrills and suspense to keep you totally immersed. The anime moves at a moderate pace, never too slow or never too hard to follow. On top of all this, the animation is very well done and the music is also good. All this makes for enjoyable watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time travel as a plot device might seem trite and the show does not try to deal with the background behind the workings of revival. No thought is given to how Revival works, or the paradoxes occurring through time travel. At one point, after failing to save Kayo, Satoru is again restored to his original time, without any explanation. This feels a little too convenient for the plot and is just sloppy writing.But given that the anime is too short to delve into all these details, this can be overlooked to enjoy its better parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One area in which the anime lacks is character development. The characters are shallow and most of them are one-dimensional and have very strange, seemingly artificial motivations. At one point in the series, Satoru finds himself at the crime scene of his murder with blood in his hands and police arriving at the scene. Out of all the possible things to do, he tries to run away from the police. Surely there were better alternatives than running away and making himself seem guilty of the crime. There is another character named Airi, who is Satoru&amp;rsquo;s coworker at a pizza delivery shop. Her father got divorced because everyone believed that he stole a chocolate even though he did not and her mother resented him for it. Nobody believed in her father, and due to this, Airi wants to believe in everybody. Very strange! There are not enough characters in the show to hide the identity of the villian. Sometimes during the show, it becomes obvious who the villain is because no other suitable character is introduced in the anime for the role. The villian is depicted as a shrewd mastermind who avoids detection by framing other people for his crimes. But the villian does not get enough screen time and his motivations are for killing lonely children are not convincing enough. But in the anime&amp;rsquo;s defense, it makes good use of its limited screen time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I will give it &lt;strong&gt;8.5 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;. Despite its flaws, it was very entertaining and kept me interested for the entirety of 4 hours. I would definitely recommend everyone to watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review - Captain Phillips</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/movie-review-captain-philips</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/movie-review-captain-philips</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are gonna shoot somebody, you shoot me. I&amp;rsquo;m the captain, not them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a8/Captain_Phillips_Poster.jpg/220px-Captain_Phillips_Poster.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the direst of situations when one of the pirates has a gun cocked to a crew-member&amp;rsquo;s head threatening to kill him if the captain did not reveal where the other crew members were hiding, he had the guts to say this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is based on the hijacking of an american ship - MV Maersk Alabama by Somali pirate in 2009. The protagonist - Captain Richard Phillips (played by Tom Hanks) is shown as a cautious man from the start ordering security drills for the crew when the ship sails off. Near the coast of Somalia they are approached by two Somali skiffs carrying armed pirates. While they are able to escape first attempt of the pirates to capture the ship, they are not so lucky the next day when pirates come with greater speed. During the course of the hijacking, the crew members hiding on the ship capture the head of the pirates and demand that all the pirates leave the ship in a life boat. The pirates(they still have captain Phillips with them) agree but the exchange for the captains go wrong and the pirates end up taking Phillips as a hostage and sail for Somalia in the life boat. Meanwhile US Navy had been deployed to tackle the issue and they arrive to save the day but not without some serious effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an excellent choice for casting, Barkhad Abdi plays Muse - the intelligent lead pirate whose character is shown with a sensitive undertone in his conversations with Captain Phillips but his determination and rage is not masked when he hits another pirate with a wrench for being a coward. His accomplice Najee played by Faysal Ahmed is shown hot-headed and ever suspicious of the actions of the Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 20 minutes, the film cashes on the momentum it had been gaining and we see gut wrenching action as Captain Phillips tries to escape and the pirates try to get the situation under control despite the dominating presence of three large US Navy ships around their lifeboat and US SEALs desperately trying grab the slightest opportunity they get to save the Captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the film is supposed to be based on a true story, be not deceived about the amount of truth in it. Cinema is meant to be larger than life and there might be more to the story of captain Phillips than told in the movie. To read more, go &lt;a href=&#34;http://nypost.com/2013/10/13/crew-members-deny-captain-phillips-heroism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A must watch for all the movie lovers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>